

SENIOR TEST CONSULTANT

□ (+46) 73-340 12 29 | soumya.saligram@gmail.com | • Github | • Linkedin

Summary

I am an engineer, with several years of experience within various areas of product testing. I enjoy automating tests, and in the process, refine the product and its value, always, with the end user in focus. Continuously collaborating with developers, product owners, account managers and testers - to best align with the use-case, while at the same time maintaining a high code coverage, are my strengths.

I am working as a **Senior Test Consultant** at **B3 Innovation AB** since January 2021, currently on a break, finishing a Linux Foundation Kubernates certification course.

In my most recent assignment as Senior QA consultant, I worked with setting up the test automation frameworks for the SJ iOS app as well as SJ's internal and public facing booking and post sales web apps. The project adheres to SAFe for aligning business and product deliveries, in which context-I contribute actively to test strategy, prioritization and evangelizing test assets reusability and optimization

Prior to this I worked as a Senior QA Test Automation Engineer at Nasdaq, Stockholm working with a TestNg-based test framework for a complex application in a challenging build environment. Prior to that, I contributed in a TestOps role in an internal React Native project, working with Android/iOS testing with Appium, Selenium WebdriverIO, ReactJs application testing with Cypress and Google Firebase integrations, X-Ray-JIRA integration and bitbucket pipelines. I have worked with setting up a Cypress test suite, applied Postman to make manual regression testing faster and repeatable. I am a certified SAFe 5.0 Agilist. I am familiar with post trade solutions and trading platforms in general (With hands-on knowledge of clearing technology for stock exchanges). Ealier in my career, I have worked for several years in industrial automation.

In my upcoming assignments as a senior QA, I look forward to applying my broad experience in various aspects of Quality Assurance, coaching, test planning and driving "shift-left" testability in exciting projects. I am ISTQB certified.

Experience

SJ Apr 2022 - Dec 2022

SENIOR TEST AUTOMATION ENGINEER

Stockholm

- Write end-to-end tests for SJ's web and IOS apps
- · Participate actively in tool selection, framework design, driving re-usability, spreading knowledge
- Setup test pipelines for end-to-test projects
- · Continous coordination with various micro services teams for testability support
- · Troubleshoot, debug, fix, avoid test flake
- Azure DevOps, Appium, Typescript, Playwright, TestNG, Java 17, Gradle7

NASDAQ Apr 2021 - Mar 2022

SENIOR TEST AUTOMATION SPECIALIST

Stockholm

- $\bullet \ \ \text{Write unit integration, functional integration tests for a complex, functionally extensive API}$
- · Participate actively in sprint planning, prioritization, identifying regression and baseline testing priorities
- Identify overlaps in large integration tests, optimize coverage with least impact to build resources and time(on CI)
- Design, execute manual exploratory, flow, scenario-based tests
- Troubleshoot, debug, fix, avoid test flake
- TestNG, Java 11, Gradle, Jenkins, Kafka

B3 Innovation AB Jan 2021 - Current

SENIOR CONSULTANT

Stockholm

- Write component tests, end-to-end tests for a React Native App
- Setup test, build and deploy dev pipelines
- Continously improve test environments for best utilization of resources
- Troubleshooting, debugging of mobile testing bottlenecks
- Cypress, ReactJs, ReactNative, Google Firebase, Bitbucket, Appium, Selenium WebdriverIO, Typescript

March 21, 2023 Soumya Prasad · Resume

Cabonline Technologies AB

May 2019 - Nov 2020

Stockholm

OA ENGINEER

- Write end-to-end tests for various web products
- Dockerize the test environment for integration into CI pipelines
- Daily monitoring of CI builds for breakages, flaky tests
- · Troubleshooting, debugging, optimization of CI/Docker bottlenecks and failures from the build log files
- · Update, track backlog on JIRA
- · Cypress, ReactJs, Docker, Jenkins, Loki, e2e testing, visual regression testing

Cinnober Financial Technology AB/NASDAQ

Sep 2017 - May 2019

Stockholm

TEST DEVELOPER

Writing functional tests for REST APIs

- · Collaborate with developers in the team, for bug fixes or tasks to be automated for the current release and/or patch delivery
- Have the tests integrated to CI pipeline/s for various work flows, as soon as possible
- · Daily monitoring of CI builds for breakages, flaky tests
- Troubleshooting, debugging of CI bottlenecks and failures from the build log files
- · Update, track backlog on JIRA
- Act as scrum master for testing sprints
- Drive consistent good performance on code quality jobs on CI
- JavaSE8, Eclipse, JUnit4, SmartGit, Python3, Confluence, JIRA, SonarCube

Yanzi Networks AB May 2017 - Jul 2017

INTERN

Stockholm

- · Testing of a websocket based REST API with Mocha/Chai libraries
- Documenting the API using LaTeX, in a unix environment
- JavaScript(ES6)
- · Mocha/Chai/BDD
- · REST API/websockets
- LaTeX

Schneider Electric Apr 2012- May 2013

ASSOCIATE LEAD Bengaluru, India

- · Worked on improving test automation with TestComplete
- · Worked closely with various scrum teams during user acceptance and release

Honeywell India Technology Labs

Dec 2005 - Mar 2012

Bengaluru, India

SENIOR ENGINEER

Define test plans and test specifications for integration, functional and performance testing, execution of test cases

• Root cause analysis and continuous process improvement(Kaizen)

GE Intelligent Systems(Emerson India)

Nov 2003 - Nov 2005

Bengaluru, India

PROJECT ENGINEER

· Study the design and technical specifications received from customer and understand the process requirements and deliverables

- Develop the main PLC logic using the Ladder language and VB scripting
- Participate in customer interactions, project reviews and software inspection

Education

SAFe 5.0 scaledagile.com/safe-50/

CERTIFICATION

CERTIFICATION

Nov 2020 - Dec 2020

· Certified SAFe 5.0 Agilist

University of Pennsylvania

coursera.org

Feb 2020 - Apr 2020

· Studied a certification course on Computational Thinking for Problem Solving

MARCH 21, 2023 SOUMYA PRASAD · RESUME Lexicon IT Konsult Feb 2017 - Jun 2017

STUDENT

- JavaSE8
- JavaEE fundamentals
- Spring/Hibernate fundamentals
- Maven fundamentals
- JUnit
- SQL fundamentals
- HTML5/CSS/JavaScript
- Eclipse IDE on Linux/Windows

Dayananda Sagar Institute of Engineering

Bengaluru, India

Stockholm

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING 1999 - 2003

• Studied Instrumentation engineering and completed course with excellent grades.

Awards_____

2009	Honeywell, Bravo-Gold:Process Excellence	Bengaluru
2007	Honeywell, ACS Special Award	Bengaluru
2006	Honeywell, Team excellence award	Bengaluru

March 21, 2023 Soumya Prasad · Resume 3